import { Question } from './types';

export const quizData: Question[] = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "Which Indian city was recently declared a UNESCO Creative City of Gastronomy?",
    options: ["Hyderabad", "Kochi", "Varanasi", "Lucknow "],
    correctAnswer: 3,
    category: "World Affairs"
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "Who won the New York City mayoral election in 2025?",
    options: ["Andrew Cuomo", "Zohran Mamdani ", "Eric Adams", "Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "World Affairs"
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "Where was the ASEAN Summit 2025 held?",
    options: ["Vietnam", "Malaysia ", "Singapore", "Thailand"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "World Affairs"
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "What is the estimated finance gap for climate adaptation in developing nations according to UNEP 2025?",
    options: ["$100–150 billion", "$200–250 billion", "$310–365 billion", "$400–450 billion"],
    correctAnswer: 2,
    category: "World Affairs"
  },
 {
    id: 5,
    question: " Which country hosted the 2025 United Nations Climate Change Conference (COP30)?",
    options: ["Germany", "Brazil", "India", "Australia"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "World Affairs"
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "Which country announced a nationwide ban on single-use plastics starting November 2025?",
    options: ["France", "Japan", "Canada", "Germany"],
    correctAnswer: 0,
    category: "World Affairs"
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: " Which Caribbean country declared independence from the British monarchy in 2025?",
    options: ["Jamaica", "Barbados", "Grenada", "Saint Kitts and Nevis"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "World Affairs"
  },
   {
    id: 8,
    question: " Which country launched the nuclear-powered underwater drone “Poseidon”?",
    options: ["USA", "China", "Russia", "North Korea"],
    correctAnswer: 2,
    category: "World Affairs"
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "What major US tech company pledged a £2 billion investment into UK AI startups in 2025?",
    options: ["Google", "Microsoft", "Nvidia", "Amazon"],
    correctAnswer: 2,
    category: "World Affairs"
  },
 {
    id: 10,
    question: " In economics, what is the name of the measure of income inequality in a population?",
    options: ["Lorenz Function", "Gini Coefficient", "Entropy Measure", "Atkinson Index"],
    correctAnswer: 1,
    category: "Economics"
  }
  
];
